Ásgeir Berg Matthíasson

asgeirberg@hi.is https://asgeirberg.org

Research interests

My current research project, which is funded by the *Icelandic Research Fund* (RANNÍS), is to develop a conventionalist account of mathematical truth, based on my previous work on the rule-following paradox and Wittgenstein's philosophy of mathematics.

Areas of Specialisation: Wittgenstein, philosophy of mathematics, philosophy of logic, the rule-following paradox.

Areas of Competence: Metaphysics, logic, epistemology, history of analytic philosophy.

Current position

Previous positions

2021 — 2022 Adjunct Lecturer
University of Iceland
 2020 — 2021 Sessional Instructor
University of Iceland
 2016 — 2019 Early Stage Researcher
University of Stirling

Education

2020 **PhD in Philosophy**, University of St Andrews and University of Stirling (SASP) Supervisors: Prof. Peter Sullivan and Prof. Crispin Wright Thesis: A defense of Wittgenstein's radical conventionalism

2015 **M.Litt. in Philosophy**, University of St Andrews and University of Stirling (SASP)

Supervisor: Prof. Peter Sullivan

Thesis: Russell's Conception of Logic in the Principles of Mathematics

2013 **M.Sc. in Logic**, University of Amsterdam

Supervisor: Prof. Martin Stokhof

Thesis: A Chalet on Mount Everest: Interpretations of Wittgenstein's Remarks on

Gödel